<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>product on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/product/</link><description>Recent content in product on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/product/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data, Design and the Product Studio</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/denver-design-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/denver-design-week/</guid><description>Title: &amp;ldquo;Data, Design and the Product Studio: A New Model for Social Change&amp;rdquo; at Design Week 2018 in Denver Colorado.
Presenters: Denise Gershbein + Aman Ahuja
In this presentation at Design Week 2018 in Denver Colorado, Denise and Aman spoke about intersections between design and data paradigms, and on a model for the product studio focused on impact.
Abstract from the Design Week program
Denise and Aman have a combined 30+ years of working in design, data science and social change.</description></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Energy Trading Platform</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</guid><description>A working peer-to-peer residential energy trading marketplace helped us understand user pains, preconceptions and motivations for trading excess energy with others.
I led a team at The Data Guild in partnership with AGL, a major Australian power company, to develop and pilot a peer-to-peer residential energy trading platform in which users with rooftop solar and battery storage could trade excess energy with others in an automated marketplace.
In the first phase of this project we worked with our Australia-based client to understand the potential impact of peer to peer markets in the relevant space, and to design an MVP that would demonstrate technical and business feasibility.</description></item></channel></rss>