<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi. I'm Aman. on Aman Ahuja</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/</link><description>Recent content in Hi. I'm Aman. on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://amanahuja.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="public-health-officials-need-better-data-driven-tools-to-make-critical-decisions-in-the-midst-of-the-pandemic">Public health officials need better data-driven tools to make critical decisions in the midst of the pandemic&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-100">
&lt;img src="http://amanahuja.me/images/cma_splash.png"
alt="Covid-19 Modeling Accelerator splash image"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>The Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative seeks to transform the approaches used for planning and operations of electricity infrastructure in developing regions. The Initiative brings together engineers and scientists from five leading research institutions to build data analytics techniques to inform energy planning that are scalable, transnational, and verified. The researchers partner with electricity service companies to develop techniques, deploy them at scale, and build capacity for data and analytics in the electricity sector.</description></item><item><title>Data sharing for the Office of Recidivism and Justice</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acamar for Clinical Trials</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/acamar-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/acamar-platform/</guid><description>Acamar was the code name for an effort led by a leadin pharmaceutical to develop a new platform for clinical trials - one which is more responsive to business needs than the incumbent offerings, and which supports trials that are significantly faster, efficient, and more transparent.</description></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Energy Trading Platform</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</guid><description>I led a team at The Data Guild in partnership with AGL, a major Australian power company, to develop and pilot a peer-to-peer residential energy trading platform in which users with rooftop solar and battery storage could trade excess energy with others in an automated marketplace.
First project phase: worked with our Australia-based client to understand the potential impact of peer to peer markets in the relevant space, and to design an MVP that would demonstrate technical and business feasibility.</description></item><item><title>DataKind SF Bay Area Chapter</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</guid><description>TYPOGRAPHY, even when poorly executed, can never be taken for granted; nor is it ever accidental. Indeed, beautifully typeset pages are always the result of long experience. Now and then they even attain the rank of great artistic achievement. But the art of typesetting stands apart from expressive artwork, because the appeal is not limited to a small circle. It is open to everyone&amp;rsquo;s critical judgment, and nowhere does this judgment carry more weight.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/about/</guid><description>Thanks for your interest in learning more about me and this website.
I should definitely replace this photo with one in which I am not wearing sunglasses. A short bio I often reuse:
Aman is a consultant, advisor and team builder with 15 years of experience helping organizations implement data tools and develop product strategies. He has worked with values-aligned initiatives in the life sciences, health, and energy sectors.</description></item><item><title>Fenris</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/pages/fenris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/pages/fenris/</guid><description>I help teams translate research and tools into responsible and impactful data products.
Through my network, Fenris, I bring together colleagues and experts to help my clients succeed. My team’s work is rooted in systems thinking, responsible data &amp;amp; AI ethics, and managing power imbalances.
In addition to data science and software development expertise, we help clients build their product strategy, technical roadmaps, and improve user adoption. We understand the importance of carefully constructed feedback loops and the delicate risk/benefit balance of outcome metrics.</description></item></channel></rss>