<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi. I'm Aman. on Aman Ahuja</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/</link><description>Recent content in Hi. I'm Aman. on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://amanahuja.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>2020 - 2021 A partnership of Rockefeller Foundation (RF), the Society for Medical Decision Making (SMDM) and Fenris, the COVID Modeling Accelerator offered modular packages of funding ($50k - $200k each) and technical assistance (including user research, product strategy, and UI design). This support was offered to academic modeling teams to create tools, dashboards, and insights for state and local decision makers and public health officials responding to COVID-19.
The team interviewed dozens of modeling teams and invited a set of candidates to apply.</description></item><item><title>Hi. I'm Aman.</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/civil_society/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/civil_society/</guid><description>I help teams translate research and tools into responsible and impactful data products.
My focus is on civil society (non profit, academic) teams seeking to improve reach, adoption, and financial independence. Through my network, Fenris, I bring together colleagues and experts to help my clients succeed. My team’s work is rooted in systems thinking, responsible data &amp;amp; AI ethics, and managing power imbalances.
In addition to data science and software development expertise, we help clients build their product strategy, technical roadmaps, and improve user adoption.</description></item><item><title>Hi. I'm Aman.</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/fenris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/fenris/</guid><description>I help teams translate research and tools into responsible and impactful data products.
Through my network, Fenris, I bring together colleagues and experts to help my clients succeed. My team’s work is rooted in systems thinking, responsible data &amp;amp; AI ethics, and managing power imbalances.
In addition to data science and software development expertise, we help clients build their product strategy, technical roadmaps, and improve user adoption. We understand the importance of carefully constructed feedback loops and the delicate risk/benefit balance of outcome metrics.</description></item><item><title>manifesto</title><link>http://amanahuja.me/manifesto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://amanahuja.me/manifesto/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>