<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Papers on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/categories/papers/</link><description>Recent content in Papers on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/categories/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Whitepaper "Ethical Algorithms for Sense and Respond Systems" for Accenture Labs</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/sense-and-respond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/sense-and-respond/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whitepaper &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Ethical Algorithms for &amp;ldquo;Sense and Respond&amp;rdquo; Systems&lt;/em>, for Accenture Labs Ethics report, 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Aman Ahuja (The Data Guild), Scott David (University of Washington), Harrison Lynch (Accenture), Seven C. Tiell (Accenture), Gideon Wulfsohn (Tufts University).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>link to
&lt;a href="https://www.academia.edu/31436602/Accenture_Labs_Ethical_algorithms_for_sense_and_respond_systems">https://www.academia.edu/31436602/Accenture_Labs_Ethical_algorithms_for_sense_and_respond_systems&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Targeted towards executives at Fortune 500 companies, this paper emphasizes the importance of ethical and thoughtful design in pervasive Sense and Respond systems, like self-driving cars.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This paper examines the ethical implications of Sense and Respond (S&amp;amp;R) systems, which are increasingly used in autonomous decision-making in various sectors, including transportation and finance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper: Predictors of Downstream Retention of Mobile Financial Services</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/mobile-retention/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/mobile-retention/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Mobile Financial Services in Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania: Downstream Prediction for Lasting Economic Retention&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. &lt;a href="cameron@thedataguild.com">Cameron Turner&lt;/a>, Aman Ahuja, and &lt;a href="david@thedataguild.com">David Gutelius&lt;/a>.
&lt;a href="https://www.academia.edu/29786468/Downstream_Retention_of_Mobile_Financial_Services_in_Kenya_Uganda_and_Tanzania">[Access via academia.edu]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this paper we sought to provide directional frameworks for mobile network operators (MNOs) and non-government organizations to better deliver digital financial services in East Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While &amp;ldquo;upstream&amp;rdquo; adoption &amp;ndash; awareness and sign-up for services &amp;ndash; is relatively well understood, there is a dearth of understanding about &amp;ldquo;downstream&amp;rdquo; retention &amp;ndash; utilization and activity beyond the initial 90 days. We surveyed available data assets that enabled meaningful longitudinal analysis of downstream retention, and proposed future work to improve data availability.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>