<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical Consultant for the Ocean Census Biodiversity Data Platform</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ocean-census-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ocean-census-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with the &lt;a href="https://www.intertidalagency.org/">Intertidal Agency&lt;/a> to provide technical consulting support for the Ocean Census Biodiversity Data Platform, a critical component of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest collaborative effort to accelerate the discovery of marine life. We provided strategic guidance during a pivotal phase of this multi-year initiative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://oceancensus.org">Ocean Census&lt;/a>, launched by The Nippon Foundation and Nekton, is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest collaborative effort to accelerate the discovery of marine life, endorsed under the United Nations Ocean Decade. The initiative brings together governments, philanthropic supporters, and leading marine research organizations to discover and document an estimated 1-2 million undiscovered marine species before they potentially go extinct.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Future of Property Rights</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</guid><description>&lt;p>I helped New America, a US public policy think tank, to define objectives and roadmaps for a multi-stakeholder initiative that advances public discourse surrounding property rights insecurity and loss in the United States. My advisory work focused on helping the team scope and plan an initiative to develop regional indicators related to housing, land, and displacement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project involved extensive data collection and indicator development work focused on housing, evictions, and housing loss. We obtained consultations from experts throughout the country to ensure methodological rigor in addressing these politically sensitive and methodologically challenging economic indicators.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>