<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ethics on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/ethics/</link><description>Recent content in Ethics on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Whitepaper "Ethical Algorithms for Sense and Respond Systems" for Accenture Labs</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/sense-and-respond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/sense-and-respond/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whitepaper &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Ethical Algorithms for &amp;ldquo;Sense and Respond&amp;rdquo; Systems&lt;/em>, for Accenture Labs Ethics report, 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Aman Ahuja (The Data Guild), Scott David (University of Washington), Harrison Lynch (Accenture), Seven C. Tiell (Accenture), Gideon Wulfsohn (Tufts University).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>link to
&lt;a href="https://www.academia.edu/31436602/Accenture_Labs_Ethical_algorithms_for_sense_and_respond_systems">https://www.academia.edu/31436602/Accenture_Labs_Ethical_algorithms_for_sense_and_respond_systems&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Targeted towards executives at Fortune 500 companies, this paper emphasizes the importance of ethical and thoughtful design in pervasive Sense and Respond systems, like self-driving cars.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This paper examines the ethical implications of Sense and Respond (S&amp;amp;R) systems, which are increasingly used in autonomous decision-making in various sectors, including transportation and finance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Historical Perspectives and Ethical Considerations in Data Science</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bids-lecture-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bids-lecture-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>This lecture at the Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) explored practial and ethical considerations of data science initiatives through their historical underpinnings. The talk aimed to provide undergraduate students an alternate perspective into their curriculum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The narrative wove together several threads of discussion:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The history of data science and statistical tools, such as factor analysis, and how they might inform our current practices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rather than viewing outliers and anomalies as mere inconveniences, Aman encouraged students to see them as opportunities for insight and exploration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drawing from years of consulting experience, Aman shared relevant stories where constraints led to unexpected outcomes or inventive solutions, offering students a glimpse into the dynamic nature of data science in practice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The lecture was supported by Berkeley Institute for Data Science and the Data, Society and Inference Seminar series. The presentation was given at 190 Doe Library on UC Berkeley campus, the newly established BIDS center.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>