<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Civil Society on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/civil-society/</link><description>Recent content in Civil Society on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/civil-society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data product strategy ands support for Global.health</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</guid><description>Fenris worked with Global.health leadership team to help align product development with long-term strategic objectives and on delivering value for the sector.
Our team helped G.h leaders refine a vision through a series of workshops. With the product team, we co-developed programs and objectives that were consistent with this vision and with constraints. Inviting input from advisors and stakeholders, a strategic product roadmap with a three-year horizon was drafted for G.</description></item><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>Overview Fenris partnered with the Society of Medical Decision Making (SMDM) and Rockefeller Foundation to help a cohort of academic research teams better meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights from epidemiological, economic and operational data models.
The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.</description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>I worked with the Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative to help set objectives, design an approach and implement a first version of their public-facing API.
About the organization e-GUIDE (https://eguide.io)
The Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative seeks to transform the approaches used for planning and operations of electricity infrastructure in developing regions.
The Initiative brings together engineers and scientists from five leading research institutions to build data analytics techniques to inform energy planning that are scalable, transnational, and verified.</description></item><item><title>Future of Property Rights</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</guid><description>I helped a New America, a US public policy think tank, to define objectives and roadmaps for a multi-stakeholder initiative that advances public discourse surrounding property rights insecurity and loss in the United States.
About the organizations New America newamerica.org:
New America is a think tank in the United States that focuses on a range of public policy issues, including national security studies, technology, asset building, health, gender, energy, education, and the economy.</description></item><item><title>Project ECHO</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</guid><description>Fenris worked with Project ECHO to provide mentorship on product strategy, build metrics, and develop reusable assets for dashboards.
Fenris collaborated with Project ECHO team on a needs assessment, data strategy discussions and metrics design. The initiative centered on two outcomes:
A set of high-level recommendations for the ECHO data and technology team The team worked together to plan, design and create a infographic “one-pager” that will be a new asset for ECHO moving forward.</description></item><item><title>DataKind SF Bay Area Chapter</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</guid><description>I founded the San Francisco Bay Area chapter of DataKind in 2013, and served as one of the chapter leaders for several years. I helped develop sustainable networks and processes for the chapter, and executed strategies for managing and training volunteers, building and supporting networks of organization-partners, and various operations.
I continue to advise and consult with DataKind Global and the Bay Area chapter.
About the organizations DataKind brings together data scientists with leading social change organizations for pro-bono collaborations to improve social impact.</description></item></channel></rss>