<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Big-Data on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/big-data/</link><description>Recent content in Big-Data on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scalable Ad-hoc Analysis of Wireless Telecommunication Transactions</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bandwidthx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bandwidthx/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Data Guild partnered with BandwidthX to design and implement a scalable analytics infrastructure for ad-hoc exploratory analysis of wireless telecommunication transaction data. The engagement provided a foundation for both the technical approach and the business case for BandwidthX&amp;rsquo;s network optimization services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BandwidthX was managing rapidly growing volumes of telecommunication transaction data from pilot programs—reaching over 1 billion records within weeks. Their existing analytics setup (a dedicated workstation running Excel and Tableau against a MySQL database) was hitting performance limits on complex queries and large dataset operations. They needed a way to run exploratory analyses quickly without disrupting production systems, while answering critical business questions about cellular savings and usage patterns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EnergySavvy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild helped develop and assess models and key performance indicators (KPIs) for energy usage. Designed methods to measure change after some event (causal inference) using counter-factuals, and corresponding uncertainty. Provided strategic direction and best practices related to code, machine learning systems, and parallelizing analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Benchmarked against the ASHRAE 14 definition of savings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New definition of energy savings based on counterfactuals &amp;amp; building models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine learning (ML) pipeline parallelization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized: python and scikit tools, starcluster spot instances on AWS compute.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman designed the ML pipeline and parallelization, implementing the savings calculation at scale. I worked with the team to assess our new savings calculation against the benchmark standard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>C3 Energy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/c3energy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/c3energy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild consulted on the development of a malfunction and theft detection system for energy utility providers. The client&amp;rsquo;s analytics engine enabled petabyte=scale grid data aggregation of historical and operational data, including smart-meter data, billing and service history, and various metadata.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our approach built on work by a team from Berkeley, innovating using a bagging and unsupervised support vector machine (SVM).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized included python-based libraries (pandas, sklearn, etc) on AWS-based parallel computation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman&amp;rsquo;s role was as a senior machine learning consultant. I helped design and implement the approach, identifying and ranking potential theft sites.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>