<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Talks on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/categories/talks/</link><description>Recent content in Talks on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/categories/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Panel: "Building Software in a Pandemic"</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/goodtechfest-building-software-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/goodtechfest-building-software-pandemic/</guid><description>This insightful panel, held during the Good Tech Fest, focused on the urgent development of software tools during the COVID-19 pandemic. The session was hosted and moderated by Evan Tachovsky of Rockfeller Foundation, co-moderated by Aman Ahuja, who also participated as a panelist.
The discussion delved into the experiences of two prominent teams. Speakers Marisa Eisenberg and Jon Zelner spoke about research at the Univerisity of Michigan, and speakers Julia Kodysh and Michal Mart reflected on their work on the Covid Tracking Project.</description></item><item><title>Panel: "Capacity Building at Nonprofits"</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ssir-capacity-building-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ssir-capacity-building-nonprofits/</guid><description>This panel discussion explored themes of building capacity for advanced data skills at nonprofits, the strategies for scaling such capacity system-wide, and the importance of multiplier organizations in the sector.
The panel, incorporating experts from diverse sectors, was moderated by Kevin Miller from the Microsoft Cities Team, alongside Kauser Razvi from Strategic Urban Solutions, Kathryn Pettit from The Urban Institute, and Aman Ahuja from Fenris.
The discussion delved into:
Roles Across Sectors: Exploring the distinct yet complementary roles of private sector entities, foundations, government bodies, and other civic actors in fostering data capacity.</description></item><item><title>Data, Design and the Product Studio</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/denver-design-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/denver-design-week/</guid><description>Title: &amp;ldquo;Data, Design and the Product Studio: A New Model for Social Change&amp;rdquo; at Design Week 2018 in Denver Colorado.
Presenters: Denise Gershbein + Aman Ahuja
In this presentation at Design Week 2018 in Denver Colorado, Denise and Aman spoke about intersections between design and data paradigms, and on a model for the product studio focused on impact.
Abstract from the Design Week program
Denise and Aman have a combined 30+ years of working in design, data science and social change.</description></item><item><title>Historical Perspectives and Ethical Considerations in Data Science</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bids-lecture-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bids-lecture-2015/</guid><description>This lecture at the Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) explored practial and ethical considerations of data science initiatives through their historical underpinnings. The talk aimed to provide undergraduate students an alternate perspective into their curriculum.
The narrative wove together several threads of discussion:
The history of data science and statistical tools, such as factor analysis, and how they might inform our current practices. Rather than viewing outliers and anomalies as mere inconveniences, Aman encouraged students to see them as opportunities for insight and exploration.</description></item></channel></rss>