<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Government on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/government/</link><description>Recent content in Government on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>International Initiative on Pandemic Prevention</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-the-initiative">About the Initiative&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major initiative with millions of dollars in funding was launched to develop computational tools for public health decisions related to disease pathogens affected by climate change. The host institute developed partnerships around the world, focusing on areas where conditions such as rising temperatures, flooding, and changing habitats are critical factors to disease prevention and response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing effective tools required collaboration between multiple stakeholders contributing data, hospitals and other providers, academics and epidemiological experts, and as a collaborator-client, local government agencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data sharing for the Office of Recidivism and Justice</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris helped design data governance and infrastructure to improve data collection, analysis and information sharing between a California county&amp;rsquo;s justice agencies. We focused on goal-setting and increased cooperation in a low-trust environment, working towards improved reentry services and reduced recidivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We partnered with the Office of Recidivism and Justice (ORJ) under the County Administrator, and through interviews and conversations worked with multiple stakeholders including the Sherriff&amp;rsquo;s office, the Probation Department, the county Court, and community based organizations (CBOs). A presentation of our methodology, deliverables, and recommendations for re-entry data management was provided in-person to the Community Corrections Partnership Executive Committee at a public forum committee meeting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EnergySavvy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild helped develop and assess models and key performance indicators (KPIs) for energy usage. Designed methods to measure change after some event (causal inference) using counter-factuals, and corresponding uncertainty. Provided strategic direction and best practices related to code, machine learning systems, and parallelizing analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Benchmarked against the ASHRAE 14 definition of savings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New definition of energy savings based on counterfactuals &amp;amp; building models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine learning (ML) pipeline parallelization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized: python and scikit tools, starcluster spot instances on AWS compute.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman designed the ML pipeline and parallelization, implementing the savings calculation at scale. I worked with the team to assess our new savings calculation against the benchmark standard.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>