<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Policy on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/policy/</link><description>Recent content in Policy on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advisor and LLM Expert for a Global Data Lab and Product Studio</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2024, Fenris began a new engagement with the &lt;a href="https://www.wri.org">World Resources Institute (WRI)&lt;/a>. WRI is an organization we&amp;rsquo;ve long admired, as home to several of the world&amp;rsquo;s most important data products in the service of climate action and human well-being.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are proud and very excited to be partnering with the Data Lab at WRI, which operates to support teams across the organization and. The Data Lab also runs an product studio, helping WRI teams develop new infrastructure, improve features, and incubate new data products. Our collaboration focuses on strengthening their product and AI innovation capacity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More Equitable Food Systems by Improving Information Flows</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/plentiful/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/plentiful/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with Plentiful using our three-phase engagement model to strengthen their data strategy and expand their impact in charitable food
systems. Working closely with their leadership team, we focused on responsible data stewardship while developing new service offerings and platform concepts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our work centered on two key initiatives: designing and analyzing a comprehensive survey of food-insecure individuals in New York City, and facilitating strategic alignment
workshops to guide Plentiful&amp;rsquo;s data platform development and revenue diversification.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mapping Global Litter Patterns for Environmental Policy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with Litterati in 2023 to conduct comprehensive geospatial analysis of litter patterns across Europe, Africa, and South America. Working with stakeholders including the World Bank and Keep Britain Tidy, we transformed real-world litter observations into actionable data for environmental policy and waste management initiatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our analysis characterized litter through systematic observation, capturing object types, materials, and brand information across diverse geographic regions. This data provided stakeholders with unprecedented insights into waste sources and the effectiveness of various intervention strategies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>International Initiative on Pandemic Prevention</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-the-initiative">About the Initiative&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major initiative with millions of dollars in funding was launched to develop computational tools for public health decisions related to disease pathogens affected by climate change. The host institute developed partnerships around the world, focusing on areas where conditions such as rising temperatures, flooding, and changing habitats are critical factors to disease prevention and response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing effective tools required collaboration between multiple stakeholders contributing data, hospitals and other providers, academics and epidemiological experts, and as a collaborator-client, local government agencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Future of Property Rights</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</guid><description>&lt;p>I helped a New America, a US public policy think tank, to define objectives and roadmaps for a multi-stakeholder initiative that advances public discourse surrounding property rights insecurity and loss in the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="about-the-organizations">About the organizations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>New America &lt;a href="https://www.newamerica.org/">newamerica.org&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>New America is a think tank in the United States that focuses on a range of public policy issues, including national security studies, technology, asset building, health, gender, energy, education, and the economy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>