<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Policy on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/policy/</link><description>Recent content in Policy on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advising Global Environmental Data Innovation at WRI</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2024, Fenris began working with the &lt;a href="https://www.wri.org">World Resources Institute (WRI)&lt;/a>. WRI has always been an organization we&amp;rsquo;ve admired, as the home of some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most important data products that are in the service of climate action and human well-being.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re proud and very excited to be partnering with WRI&amp;rsquo;s Data Lab, which operates to support teams across the organozation and and runs an internal product studio, helping WRI teams develop new infrastructure, improved features, and completely new data products. Our collaboration focuses on strengthening their product and AI innovation capacity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mapping Global Litter Patterns for Environmental Policy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with Litterati in 2023 to conduct comprehensive geospatial analysis of litter patterns across Europe, Africa, and South America. Working with stakeholders including the World Bank and Keep Britain Tidy, we transformed real-world litter observations into actionable data for environmental policy and waste management initiatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our analysis characterized litter through systematic observation, capturing object types, materials, and brand information across diverse geographic regions. This data provided stakeholders with unprecedented insights into waste sources and the effectiveness of various intervention strategies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>