<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nonprofit on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/nonprofit/</link><description>Recent content in Nonprofit on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/nonprofit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Panel: "Capacity Building at Nonprofits"</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ssir-capacity-building-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ssir-capacity-building-nonprofits/</guid><description>&lt;p>This panel discussion explored themes of building capacity for advanced data skills at nonprofits, the strategies for scaling such capacity system-wide, and the importance of multiplier organizations in the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The panel, incorporating experts from diverse sectors, was moderated by Kevin Miller from the Microsoft Cities Team, alongside Kauser Razvi from Strategic Urban Solutions, Kathryn Pettit from The Urban Institute, and Aman Ahuja from Fenris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The discussion delved into:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Roles Across Sectors&lt;/strong>: Exploring the distinct yet complementary roles of private sector entities, foundations, government bodies, and other civic actors in fostering data capacity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Capacity Building Elements&lt;/strong>: Identifying key factors that contribute to successful capacity building, particularly in the context of advanced technologies like ML and AI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Scalability Challenges&lt;/strong>: Discussing strategies to effectively scale up capacity-building initiatives for substantial, system-wide impact.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This panel discussion drew upon Aman&amp;rsquo;s expertise in the intersection of data science and nonprofit sector capacity building, contributing valuable insights into the evolution of data competencies in civic spaces.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>