<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1900 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="public-health-officials-need-better-data-driven-tools-to-make-critical-decisions-in-the-midst-of-the-pandemic">Public health officials need better data-driven tools to make critical decisions in the midst of the pandemic&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-100">
&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/cma_splash.png"
alt="Covid-19 Modeling Accelerator splash image"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>I worked with the Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative to help set objectives, design an approach and implement a first version of their public-facing API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The eGUIDE initiative was created by academic teams&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Platform for Clinical Trials</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/acamar-platform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/acamar-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Guild worked with one of the largest pharmaceutical companies in the world to develop a new approach to data sharing in clinical research. The immediate objective was to decrease the time and increase the efficiency of clinical trials, and design principles centered openness, transparency, and improved outcomes for patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data sharing for the Office of Recidivism and Justice</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris helped a California county office design governance and infrastructure to improve data collection, analysis and information sharing across agencies and contracted service providers towards improved reentry services and reduced recidivism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Energy Trading Platform</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="using-a-protype-to-learn-about-user-pains-preconceptions-and-motivations-for-sharing-energy-with-their-friends-and-family">Using a protype to learn about user pains, preconceptions and motivations for sharing energy with their friends and family&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I led a team at The Data Guild in partnership with AGL, a major Australian power company, to develop and pilot a peer-to-peer residential energy trading platform in which users with rooftop solar and battery storage could trade excess energy with others in an automated marketplace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DataKind SF Bay Area Chapter</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</guid><description>I founded the San Francisco Bay Area chapter of DataKind in 2013, and served as one of the chapter leaders for several years. I helped develop sustainable networks and processes for the chapter, and executed strategies for managing and training volunteers, building and supporting networks of organization-partners, and various operations.
I continue to advise and consult with DataKind Global and the Bay Area chapter.
DataKind brings together data scientists with leading social change organizations for pro-bono collaborations to improve social impact.</description></item></channel></rss>