<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Charitable Food Systems</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/plentiful/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/plentiful/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-plentiful">About Plentiful&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Plentiful is a social impact organization that works to create more connected charitable food ecosystems, enhancing dignity for food insecure individuals and building more equitable communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- 
Notes or comments here
* 
Food charity triangle improving connections and information flow
NYC Mayor's office of food policy
Food assistance collaborative
provided advisory and coaching for executing a survey of food insucure individuals in NYC
helped improved response rate
helped setup analysis of survey responses and delivering valuable insights 
expanding from one geography to more geographies
contributed to Plentiful's theory of change and business model
conducted a workshop in Denver
platform that connects food service providers in NYC, making resources more accessible
Possibly involved in the transition from a "push" to "pull" model in food assistance
Experience with social impact technology in the food security space
Data visualization and monitoring system implementation
Strategic work transforming charitable food distribution models
Contribution to a platform that directly improves access to essential services for vulnerable populations
pricing models


Overview
* 13 units, which are simply 2-week chunks of work. 
* Sync-Async rhythm: A unit might include meeting as a team for an activity we do together, and async collaboration on a document as lead-in or followup. 
* Timeline: there are about 13 total units in these 6 months, allowing for some flexibility and "space" between units. 

We worked on
* NYC MOFP project at Plentiful overview
* Data strategy notes for Plentiful 2024 —> update with final
* Boundless project at Plentiful
* Plentiful workshop in Denver April 2024
* Plentiful 1-on-1 checkins with team

### About Plentiful

Plentiful is a social impact organization that works to create more connected charitable food ecosystems, enhancing dignity for food insecure individuals and building more equitable communities.


--></description></item><item><title>Mapping Global Litter Patterns for Environmental Policy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with Litterati in 2023 to conduct comprehensive geospatial analysis of litter patterns across Europe, Africa, and South America. Working with stakeholders including the World Bank and Keep Britain Tidy, we transformed real-world litter observations into actionable data for environmental policy and waste management initiatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our analysis characterized litter through systematic observation, capturing object types, materials, and brand information across diverse geographic regions. This data provided stakeholders with unprecedented insights into waste sources and the effectiveness of various intervention strategies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A digital space for global collaboration on Epidemic and Pandemic Intelligence</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalpandemichub/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalpandemichub/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our client was a well-resourced and internationally recognized team working
with governments and major stakeholders around the world to create a digital
space that supports collaboration among the global epidemic intelligence community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project&amp;rsquo;s stated objective was to create&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A digital environment where subject experts and the epidemic and pandemic
intelligence community converge to communicate, cultivate ideas and
co-develop, to rapidly generate and provide community-driven solutions to
address existing challenges and needs in the domain of data, analytics, and
evidence-based decision-making.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>International Initiative on Pandemic Prevention</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-the-initiative">About the Initiative&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major initiative with millions of dollars in funding was launched to develop computational tools for public health decisions related to disease pathogens affected by climate change. The host institute developed partnerships around the world, focusing on areas where conditions such as rising temperatures, flooding, and changing habitats are critical factors to disease prevention and response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing effective tools required collaboration between multiple stakeholders contributing data, hospitals and other providers, academics and epidemiological experts, and as a collaborator-client, local government agencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Leadership Cohort</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/data-leadership-cohort/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/data-leadership-cohort/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2022, Fenris, along with Aspiration and Digital Public, launched a new
program on data leadership and governance. The Data Leadership Cohort was
designed to create opportunities for leaders to learn from peers about
governance, stewardship and long-term responsible leadership in data-centric
missions and ventures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Data Leadership Cohort brought together Aspiration’s field-leading and
tested frameworks for peer learning, Digital Public’s expertise in public
interest data governance, and practical expertise from Fenris for integrating
these ideas into team, process and product.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global.health</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris worked with the Global.health leadership team to help align product development with long-term strategic objectives and to deliver value for the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our team helped G.h leaders refine a vision through a series of workshops. With the product team, we co-developed programs and objectives that were consistent with this vision and with constraints. Inviting input from advisors and stakeholders, a &lt;em>strategic product roadmap&lt;/em> with a three-year horizon was drafted for G.h, and aligned with funding opportunities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-100">&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/cma_splash.png"
 alt="Covid-19 Modeling Accelerator splash image">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Fenris partnered with the Society for Medical Decision Making (SMDM) and Rockefeller Foundation to help a cohort of academic research teams better meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights from epidemiological, economic and operational data models.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aman worked with the Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative to help set objectives, design an approach and implement a first version of their public-facing API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Fenris engagement helped center the team’s collaborations and Initiative partnerships. Following best practices for user-centered API design, we helped the team challenge their own assumptions about the value and utility of the consumption prediction models. Aman also provided technical mentorship and collaboration with the engineering lead.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Future of Property Rights</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</guid><description>&lt;p>I helped a New America, a US public policy think tank, to define objectives and roadmaps for a multi-stakeholder initiative that advances public discourse surrounding property rights insecurity and loss in the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="about-the-organizations">About the organizations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>New America &lt;a href="https://www.newamerica.org/">newamerica.org&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>New America is a think tank in the United States that focuses on a range of public policy issues, including national security studies, technology, asset building, health, gender, energy, education, and the economy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project ECHO</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris worked with Project ECHO to provide mentorship on product strategy, build metrics, and develop reusable assets for dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fenris collaborated with Project ECHO team on a needs assessment, data strategy discussions and metrics design. The initiative centered on two outcomes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A set of high-level recommendations for the ECHO data and technology team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The team worked together to plan, design and create a infographic “one-pager” that will be a new asset for ECHO moving forward.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/echo_02.png" alt="US Counties map">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Panel: "Building Software in a Pandemic"</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/goodtechfest-building-software-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/goodtechfest-building-software-pandemic/</guid><description>&lt;p>This insightful panel, held during the Good Tech Fest, focused on the urgent development of software tools during the COVID-19 pandemic. The session was hosted and moderated by Evan Tachovsky of Rockfeller Foundation, co-moderated by Aman Ahuja, who also participated as a panelist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The discussion delved into the experiences of two prominent teams. Speakers Marisa Eisenberg and Jon Zelner spoke about research at the Univerisity of Michigan, and speakers Julia Kodysh and Michal Mart reflected on their work on the Covid Tracking Project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Panel: "Capacity Building at Nonprofits"</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ssir-capacity-building-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ssir-capacity-building-nonprofits/</guid><description>&lt;p>This panel discussion explored themes of building capacity for advanced data skills at nonprofits, the strategies for scaling such capacity system-wide, and the importance of multiplier organizations in the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The panel, incorporating experts from diverse sectors, was moderated by Kevin Miller from the Microsoft Cities Team, alongside Kauser Razvi from Strategic Urban Solutions, Kathryn Pettit from The Urban Institute, and Aman Ahuja from Fenris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The discussion delved into:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Roles Across Sectors&lt;/strong>: Exploring the distinct yet complementary roles of private sector entities, foundations, government bodies, and other civic actors in fostering data capacity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Capacity Building Elements&lt;/strong>: Identifying key factors that contribute to successful capacity building, particularly in the context of advanced technologies like ML and AI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Scalability Challenges&lt;/strong>: Discussing strategies to effectively scale up capacity-building initiatives for substantial, system-wide impact.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This panel discussion drew upon Aman&amp;rsquo;s expertise in the intersection of data science and nonprofit sector capacity building, contributing valuable insights into the evolution of data competencies in civic spaces.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CEA Pod</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/tdg-cea-pod/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/tdg-cea-pod/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild ran a research &amp;ldquo;pod&amp;rdquo; to explore recent advancements in controlled environment agriculture. CEA has the potential to address areas of concern to the Guild: energy efficiency, human health, economic development, water and resource conservation, and climate resilience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pod followed a structured methodology to understand the landscape of important players in this space, generate a simplified systems map, and to identify intersections with the Guild&amp;rsquo;s strengths and related efforts. The pod members conducted interviews with experts and visited several CEA facilities. Among the outputs was several proposals for data products, each with a preliminary business canvas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data, Design and the Product Studio</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/denver-design-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/denver-design-week/</guid><description>&lt;p>Title: &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Data, Design and the Product Studio: A New Model for Social Change&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> at Design Week 2018 in Denver Colorado.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presenters: Denise Gershbein + Aman Ahuja&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this presentation at Design Week 2018 in Denver Colorado, Denise and Aman spoke about intersections between design and data paradigms, and on a model for the product studio focused on impact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract from the Design Week program&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Denise and Aman have a combined 30+ years of working in design, data science and social change. Their work often targets impact through seeking levers in the system &amp;ndash; working at several levels at once to influence, build capacity, and release solutions that affect the system in multiple places, with a cascading effect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Platform for Clinical Trials</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/acamar-platform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/acamar-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Guild worked with one of the largest pharmaceutical companies in the world to develop a new approach to data sharing in clinical research. The immediate objective was to decrease the time and increase the efficiency of clinical trials. We developed design principles that centered openness, transparency, and improved outcomes for patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The approach centered an open technical platform with independent governance to guarantee the compliance, quality, and interoperability of software offerings in clinical trials. By working at the center of clinical data systems and their partners, the Guild identified a range of new data- and AI-enabled clinical research capabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data sharing for the Office of Recidivism and Justice</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris helped design data governance and infrastructure to improve data collection, analysis and information sharing between a California county&amp;rsquo;s justice agencies. We focused on goal-setting and increased cooperation in a low-trust environment, working towards improved reentry services and reduced recidivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We partnered with the Office of Recidivism and Justice (ORJ) under the County Administrator, and through interviews and conversations worked with multiple stakeholders including the Sherriff&amp;rsquo;s office, the Probation Department, the county Court, and community based organizations (CBOs). A presentation of our methodology, deliverables, and recommendations for re-entry data management was provided in-person to the Community Corrections Partnership Executive Committee at a public forum committee meeting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Energy Trading Platform</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</guid><description>&lt;p>A working peer-to-peer residential energy trading marketplace helped us understand user pains, preconceptions and motivations for trading excess energy with others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I led a team at The Data Guild in partnership with AGL, a major Australian power company, to develop and pilot a peer-to-peer residential energy trading platform in which users with rooftop solar and battery storage could trade excess energy with others in an automated marketplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first phase of this project we worked with our Australia-based client to understand the potential impact of peer to peer markets in the relevant space, and to design an MVP that would demonstrate technical and business feasibility. In the second phase, we assembled a technical, design, and user research team to build a working MVP, deploy with a pilot population, and understand user reactions and motivations for the marketplace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Whitepaper "Ethical Algorithms for Sense and Respond Systems" for Accenture Labs</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/sense-and-respond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/sense-and-respond/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whitepaper &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Ethical Algorithms for &amp;ldquo;Sense and Respond&amp;rdquo; Systems&lt;/em>, for Accenture Labs Ethics report, 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Aman Ahuja (The Data Guild), Scott David (University of Washington), Harrison Lynch (Accenture), Seven C. Tiell (Accenture), Gideon Wulfsohn (Tufts University).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>link to
&lt;a href="https://www.academia.edu/31436602/Accenture_Labs_Ethical_algorithms_for_sense_and_respond_systems">https://www.academia.edu/31436602/Accenture_Labs_Ethical_algorithms_for_sense_and_respond_systems&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Targeted towards executives at Fortune 500 companies, this paper emphasizes the importance of ethical and thoughtful design in pervasive Sense and Respond systems, like self-driving cars.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This paper examines the ethical implications of Sense and Respond (S&amp;amp;R) systems, which are increasingly used in autonomous decision-making in various sectors, including transportation and finance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DataKind SF Bay Area Chapter</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</guid><description>&lt;p>I founded the San Francisco Bay Area chapter of DataKind in 2013, and served as one of the chapter leaders for several years. I helped develop sustainable networks and processes for the chapter, and executed strategies for managing and training volunteers, building and supporting networks of organization-partners, and various operations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I continue to advise and consult with DataKind Global and the Bay Area chapter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="about-the-organizations">About the organizations&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-third">&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/logos/datakind_logo_orange.png"
 alt="DataKind logo">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.datakind.org/">DataKind&lt;/a> brings together data scientists with leading social change organizations for pro-bono collaborations to improve social impact. The &lt;a href="https://www.datakind.org/chapters/datakind-sf">DataKindSF chapter&lt;/a> supports goverment, non profits, and other social change organizations with a presence in San Francisco, Alameda, San Mateo, Santa Clara, and other counties in the SF Bay Area.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper: Predictors of Downstream Retention of Mobile Financial Services</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/mobile-retention/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/mobile-retention/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Mobile Financial Services in Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania: Downstream Prediction for Lasting Economic Retention&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. &lt;a href="cameron@thedataguild.com">Cameron Turner&lt;/a>, Aman Ahuja, and &lt;a href="david@thedataguild.com">David Gutelius&lt;/a>.
&lt;a href="https://www.academia.edu/29786468/Downstream_Retention_of_Mobile_Financial_Services_in_Kenya_Uganda_and_Tanzania">[Access via academia.edu]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this paper we sought to provide directional frameworks for mobile network operators (MNOs) and non-government organizations to better deliver digital financial services in East Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While &amp;ldquo;upstream&amp;rdquo; adoption &amp;ndash; awareness and sign-up for services &amp;ndash; is relatively well understood, there is a dearth of understanding about &amp;ldquo;downstream&amp;rdquo; retention &amp;ndash; utilization and activity beyond the initial 90 days. We surveyed available data assets that enabled meaningful longitudinal analysis of downstream retention, and proposed future work to improve data availability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Historical Perspectives and Ethical Considerations in Data Science</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bids-lecture-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/bids-lecture-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>This lecture at the Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) explored practial and ethical considerations of data science initiatives through their historical underpinnings. The talk aimed to provide undergraduate students an alternate perspective into their curriculum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The narrative wove together several threads of discussion:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The history of data science and statistical tools, such as factor analysis, and how they might inform our current practices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rather than viewing outliers and anomalies as mere inconveniences, Aman encouraged students to see them as opportunities for insight and exploration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drawing from years of consulting experience, Aman shared relevant stories where constraints led to unexpected outcomes or inventive solutions, offering students a glimpse into the dynamic nature of data science in practice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The lecture was supported by Berkeley Institute for Data Science and the Data, Society and Inference Seminar series. The presentation was given at 190 Doe Library on UC Berkeley campus, the newly established BIDS center.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proteus Digital Health</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/proteus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/proteus/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Data Guild advised on strategic approach to develop new market opportunities for a medical device company in the wearable space. One concept explored recovery cycle applications for professional athletes. Device interfaced with mobile device through an application with FDA regulatory considerations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our team also developed and tested the &amp;ldquo;recovery&amp;rdquo; calculation for the pilot, utilizing biometric data such as heart rate to calculate sleep and orthostatic stress conditions for individuals wearing the device.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EnergySavvy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild helped develop and assess models and key performance indicators (KPIs) for energy usage. Designed methods to measure change after some event (causal inference) using counter-factuals, and corresponding uncertainty. Provided strategic direction and best practices related to code, machine learning systems, and parallelizing analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Benchmarked against the ASHRAE 14 definition of savings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New definition of energy savings based on counterfactuals &amp;amp; building models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine learning (ML) pipeline parallelization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized: python and scikit tools, starcluster spot instances on AWS compute.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman designed the ML pipeline and parallelization, implementing the savings calculation at scale. I worked with the team to assess our new savings calculation against the benchmark standard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>C3 Energy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/c3energy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/c3energy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild consulted on the development of a malfunction and theft detection system for energy utility providers. The client&amp;rsquo;s analytics engine enabled petabyte=scale grid data aggregation of historical and operational data, including smart-meter data, billing and service history, and various metadata.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our approach built on work by a team from Berkeley, innovating using a bagging and unsupervised support vector machine (SVM).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized included python-based libraries (pandas, sklearn, etc) on AWS-based parallel computation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman&amp;rsquo;s role was as a senior machine learning consultant. I helped design and implement the approach, identifying and ranking potential theft sites.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>