<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Epidemiology on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/epidemiology/</link><description>Recent content in Epidemiology on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A digital space for global collaboration on Epidemic and Pandemic Intelligence</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalpandemichub/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalpandemichub/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our client was a well-resourced and internationally recognized team working
with governments and major stakeholders around the world to create a digital
space that supports collaboration among the global epidemic intelligence community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project&amp;rsquo;s stated objective was to create&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A digital environment where subject experts and the epidemic and pandemic
intelligence community converge to communicate, cultivate ideas and
co-develop, to rapidly generate and provide community-driven solutions to
address existing challenges and needs in the domain of data, analytics, and
evidence-based decision-making.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>International Initiative on Pandemic Prevention</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-the-initiative">About the Initiative&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major initiative with millions of dollars in funding was launched to develop computational tools for public health decisions related to disease pathogens affected by climate change. The host institute developed partnerships around the world, focusing on areas where conditions such as rising temperatures, flooding, and changing habitats are critical factors to disease prevention and response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing effective tools required collaboration between multiple stakeholders contributing data, hospitals and other providers, academics and epidemiological experts, and as a collaborator-client, local government agencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global.health</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris worked with the Global.health leadership team to develop a multi-year strategy and product roadmap that translated their global mission into phased, fundable execution steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our team helped G.h leaders refine a vision through a series of workshops. With the product team, we co-developed programs and objectives that were consistent with this vision and with constraints. The sequencing was carefully designed based on data readiness, governance requirements, and operating capacity of the organization.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>