<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Climate on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/climate/</link><description>Recent content in Climate on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical Consultant for the Ocean Census Biodiversity Data Platform</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ocean-census-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/ocean-census-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with the &lt;a href="https://www.intertidalagency.org/">Intertidal Agency&lt;/a> to provide technical consulting support for the Ocean Census Biodiversity Data Platform, a critical component of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest collaborative effort to accelerate the discovery of marine life. We provided strategic guidance during a pivotal phase of this multi-year initiative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://oceancensus.org">Ocean Census&lt;/a>, launched by The Nippon Foundation and Nekton, is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest collaborative effort to accelerate the discovery of marine life, endorsed under the United Nations Ocean Decade. The initiative brings together governments, philanthropic supporters, and leading marine research organizations to discover and document an estimated 1-2 million undiscovered marine species before they potentially go extinct.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advisor and LLM Expert for a Global Data Lab and Product Studio</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2024, Fenris began a new engagement with the &lt;a href="https://www.wri.org">World Resources Institute (WRI)&lt;/a>. WRI is an organization we&amp;rsquo;ve long admired, as home to several of the world&amp;rsquo;s most important data products in the service of climate action and human well-being. This significant client relationship demonstrates Fenris&amp;rsquo;s recognition as an expert in both data product strategy and generative AI technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are proud and very excited to be partnering with the Data Lab at WRI, which operates to support teams across the organization. The Data Lab also runs a product studio, helping WRI teams develop new infrastructure, improve features, and incubate new data products. Our collaboration focuses on strengthening their product and AI innovation capacity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>International Initiative on Pandemic Prevention</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-the-initiative">About the Initiative&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major initiative with millions of dollars in funding was launched to develop computational tools for public health decisions related to disease pathogens affected by climate change. The host institute developed partnerships around the world, focusing on areas where conditions such as rising temperatures, flooding, and changing habitats are critical factors to disease prevention and response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing effective tools required collaboration between multiple stakeholders contributing data, hospitals and other providers, academics and epidemiological experts, and as a collaborator-client, local government agencies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>