<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Energy on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/energy/</link><description>Recent content in Energy on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advisor and LLM Expert for a Global Data Lab and Product Studio</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/wri-year-one/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2024, Fenris began a new engagement with the &lt;a href="https://www.wri.org">World Resources Institute (WRI)&lt;/a>. WRI is an organization we&amp;rsquo;ve long admired, as home to several of the world&amp;rsquo;s most important data products in the service of climate action and human well-being. This significant client relationship demonstrates Fenris&amp;rsquo;s recognition as an expert in both data product strategy and generative AI technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are proud and very excited to be partnering with the Data Lab at WRI, which operates to support teams across the organization. The Data Lab also runs a product studio, helping WRI teams develop new infrastructure, improve features, and incubate new data products. Our collaboration focuses on strengthening their product and AI innovation capacity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aman worked with the Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative to help set objectives, design an approach and implement a first version of their public-facing API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Fenris engagement helped center the team’s collaborations and Initiative partnerships. Following best practices for user-centered API design, we helped the team challenge their own assumptions about the value and utility of the consumption prediction models. Aman also provided technical mentorship and collaboration with the engineering lead.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Energy Trading Platform</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/p2p-energy-trading/</guid><description>&lt;p>A working peer-to-peer residential energy trading marketplace helped us understand user pains, preconceptions and motivations for trading excess energy with others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I led a team at The Data Guild in partnership with AGL, a major Australian power company, to develop and pilot a peer-to-peer residential energy trading platform in which users with rooftop solar and battery storage could trade excess energy with others in an automated marketplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first phase of this project we worked with our Australia-based client to understand the potential impact of peer to peer markets in the relevant space, and to design an MVP that would demonstrate technical and business feasibility. In the second phase, we assembled a technical, design, and user research team to build a working MVP, deploy with a pilot population, and understand user reactions and motivations for the marketplace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EnergySavvy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/energysavvy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild helped develop and assess models and key performance indicators (KPIs) for energy usage. Designed methods to measure change after some event (causal inference) using counter-factuals, and corresponding uncertainty. Provided strategic direction and best practices related to code, machine learning systems, and parallelizing analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Benchmarked against the ASHRAE 14 definition of savings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New definition of energy savings based on counterfactuals &amp;amp; building models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine learning (ML) pipeline parallelization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized: python and scikit tools, starcluster spot instances on AWS compute.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman designed the ML pipeline and parallelization, implementing the savings calculation at scale. I worked with the team to assess our new savings calculation against the benchmark standard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>C3 Energy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/c3energy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/c3energy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Guild consulted on the development of a malfunction and theft detection system for energy utility providers. The client&amp;rsquo;s analytics engine enabled petabyte=scale grid data aggregation of historical and operational data, including smart-meter data, billing and service history, and various metadata.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our approach built on work by a team from Berkeley, innovating using a bagging and unsupervised support vector machine (SVM).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technologies utilized included python-based libraries (pandas, sklearn, etc) on AWS-based parallel computation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aman&amp;rsquo;s role was as a senior machine learning consultant. I helped design and implement the approach, identifying and ranking potential theft sites.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>