<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Public Sector on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/tags/public-sector/</link><description>Recent content in Public Sector on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/tags/public-sector/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-100">&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/cma_splash.png"
 alt="Covid-19 Modeling Accelerator splash image">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Fenris partnered with the Society for Medical Decision Making (SMDM) and Rockefeller Foundation to help a cohort of academic research teams better meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights from epidemiological, economic and operational data models.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DataKind SF Bay Area Chapter</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/datakind-sf/</guid><description>&lt;p>I founded the San Francisco Bay Area chapter of DataKind in 2013, and served as one of the chapter leaders for several years. I helped develop sustainable networks and processes for the chapter, and executed strategies for managing and training volunteers, building and supporting networks of organization-partners, and various operations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I continue to advise and consult with DataKind Global and the Bay Area chapter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="about-the-organizations">About the organizations&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-third">&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/logos/datakind_logo_orange.png"
 alt="DataKind logo">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.datakind.org/">DataKind&lt;/a> brings together data scientists with leading social change organizations for pro-bono collaborations to improve social impact. The &lt;a href="https://www.datakind.org/chapters/datakind-sf">DataKindSF chapter&lt;/a> supports goverment, non profits, and other social change organizations with a presence in San Francisco, Alameda, San Mateo, Santa Clara, and other counties in the SF Bay Area.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>