<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fenris on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/series/fenris/</link><description>Recent content in Fenris on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/series/fenris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Equitable Food Systems Through Data and Strategy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/plentiful/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/plentiful/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with Plentiful with our three-phase engagement model to strengthen their data strategy and expand their impact in charitable food
systems. Working closely with their leadership team, we focused on responsible data stewardship while developing new service offerings and platform concepts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our engagement centered on two key initiatives: designing and analyzing a comprehensive survey of food-insecure individuals in New York City, and facilitating strategic alignment
workshops to guide Plentiful&amp;rsquo;s data platform development and revenue diversification.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mapping Global Litter Patterns for Environmental Policy</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/litterati-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris partnered with Litterati in 2023 to conduct comprehensive geospatial analysis of litter patterns across Europe, Africa, and South America. Working with stakeholders including the World Bank and Keep Britain Tidy, we transformed real-world litter observations into actionable data for environmental policy and waste management initiatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our analysis characterized litter through systematic observation, capturing object types, materials, and brand information across diverse geographic regions. This data provided stakeholders with unprecedented insights into waste sources and the effectiveness of various intervention strategies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A digital space for global collaboration on Epidemic and Pandemic Intelligence</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalpandemichub/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalpandemichub/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our client was a well-resourced and internationally recognized team working
with governments and major stakeholders around the world to create a digital
space that supports collaboration among the global epidemic intelligence community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project&amp;rsquo;s stated objective was to create&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A digital environment where subject experts and the epidemic and pandemic
intelligence community converge to communicate, cultivate ideas and
co-develop, to rapidly generate and provide community-driven solutions to
address existing challenges and needs in the domain of data, analytics, and
evidence-based decision-making.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>International Initiative on Pandemic Prevention</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/dengue-public-health/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-the-initiative">About the Initiative&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major initiative with millions of dollars in funding was launched to develop computational tools for public health decisions related to disease pathogens affected by climate change. The host institute developed partnerships around the world, focusing on areas where conditions such as rising temperatures, flooding, and changing habitats are critical factors to disease prevention and response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing effective tools required collaboration between multiple stakeholders contributing data, hospitals and other providers, academics and epidemiological experts, and as a collaborator-client, local government agencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global.health</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/globalhealth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris worked with the Global.health leadership team to help align product development with long-term strategic objectives and to deliver value for the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our team helped G.h leaders refine a vision through a series of workshops. With the product team, we co-developed programs and objectives that were consistent with this vision and with constraints. Inviting input from advisors and stakeholders, a &lt;em>strategic product roadmap&lt;/em> with a three-year horizon was drafted for G.h, and aligned with funding opportunities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="db mh0 w-100">&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/cma_splash.png"
 alt="Covid-19 Modeling Accelerator splash image">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Fenris partnered with the Society for Medical Decision Making (SMDM) and Rockefeller Foundation to help a cohort of academic research teams better meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights from epidemiological, economic and operational data models.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aman worked with the Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative to help set objectives, design an approach and implement a first version of their public-facing API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Fenris engagement helped center the team’s collaborations and Initiative partnerships. Following best practices for user-centered API design, we helped the team challenge their own assumptions about the value and utility of the consumption prediction models. Aman also provided technical mentorship and collaboration with the engineering lead.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Future of Property Rights</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</guid><description>&lt;p>I helped a New America, a US public policy think tank, to define objectives and roadmaps for a multi-stakeholder initiative that advances public discourse surrounding property rights insecurity and loss in the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="about-the-organizations">About the organizations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>New America &lt;a href="https://www.newamerica.org/">newamerica.org&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>New America is a think tank in the United States that focuses on a range of public policy issues, including national security studies, technology, asset building, health, gender, energy, education, and the economy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project ECHO</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris worked with Project ECHO to provide mentorship on product strategy, build metrics, and develop reusable assets for dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fenris collaborated with Project ECHO team on a needs assessment, data strategy discussions and metrics design. The initiative centered on two outcomes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A set of high-level recommendations for the ECHO data and technology team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The team worked together to plan, design and create a infographic “one-pager” that will be a new asset for ECHO moving forward.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://amanahuja.me/images/echo_02.png" alt="US Counties map">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data sharing for the Office of Recidivism and Justice</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fenris helped design data governance and infrastructure to improve data collection, analysis and information sharing between a California county&amp;rsquo;s justice agencies. We focused on goal-setting and increased cooperation in a low-trust environment, working towards improved reentry services and reduced recidivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We partnered with the Office of Recidivism and Justice (ORJ) under the County Administrator, and through interviews and conversations worked with multiple stakeholders including the Sherriff&amp;rsquo;s office, the Probation Department, the county Court, and community based organizations (CBOs). A presentation of our methodology, deliverables, and recommendations for re-entry data management was provided in-person to the Community Corrections Partnership Executive Committee at a public forum committee meeting.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>