<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fenris on Aman Ahuja</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/series/fenris/</link><description>Recent content in Fenris on Aman Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanahuja.me/series/fenris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID Modeling Accelerator</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/covid-modeling-accelerator/</guid><description>Overview Fenris partnered with the Society of Medical Decision Making (SMDM) and Rockefeller Foundation to help a cohort of academic research teams better meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights from epidemiological, economic and operational data models.
The COVID Modeling Accelerator was created to support a cohort of academic research teams to meet the needs of state and local decision-makers for actionable insights to better respond to the unprecedented challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic.</description></item><item><title>eGUIDE Products for Energy Planning</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/eguide-api/</guid><description>I worked with the Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative to help set objectives, design an approach and implement a first version of their public-facing API.
About the organization e-GUIDE (https://eguide.io)
The Electricity Growth and Use in Developing Economies (e-GUIDE) Initiative seeks to transform the approaches used for planning and operations of electricity infrastructure in developing regions.
The Initiative brings together engineers and scientists from five leading research institutions to build data analytics techniques to inform energy planning that are scalable, transnational, and verified.</description></item><item><title>Future of Property Rights</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/future-property-rights/</guid><description>I helped a New America, a US public policy think tank, to define objectives and roadmaps for a multi-stakeholder initiative that advances public discourse surrounding property rights insecurity and loss in the United States.
About the organizations New America newamerica.org:
New America is a think tank in the United States that focuses on a range of public policy issues, including national security studies, technology, asset building, health, gender, energy, education, and the economy.</description></item><item><title>Project ECHO</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/project-echo/</guid><description>Fenris worked with Project ECHO to provide mentorship on product strategy, build metrics, and develop reusable assets for dashboards.
Fenris collaborated with Project ECHO team on a needs assessment, data strategy discussions and metrics design. The initiative centered on two outcomes:
A set of high-level recommendations for the ECHO data and technology team The team worked together to plan, design and create a infographic “one-pager” that will be a new asset for ECHO moving forward.</description></item><item><title>Data sharing for the Office of Recidivism and Justice</title><link>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amanahuja.me/portfolio/recidivism-data-sharing/</guid><description>Fenris helped a California county office design governance and infrastructure to improve data collection, analysis and information sharing across agencies and contracted service providers towards improved reentry services and reduced recidivism.
We partnered with the Office of Recidivism and Justice (ORJ) under the County Administrator, and through interviews and conversations worked with multiple stakeholders including the Sherriff&amp;rsquo;s office, the Probation Department, the county Court, and community based organizations (CBOs). A presentation of our methodology, deliverables, and recommendations for re-entry data management was provided in-person to the Community Corrections Partnership Executive Committee at a public forum committee meeting.</description></item></channel></rss>